Guide to the Cap and Gown Society (Stanford University) records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Cap and Gown Society (Stanford University) records
1906-2007
SC0909
Cap and Gown Society (Stanford University).
4 Linear feet (8 boxes)
The records include constitution; newsletters, 1932-2007; the yearly calendar illustrated with images of Stanford University, 1941-1983; membership book 1906-1996; history booklets, programs, brochures and mailings; photographs and printed items from their Centennial Celebration on March 5, 2005; other photographs, 1965-1997; survey of alumni, 1996; and clippings, 1965-1983.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research; materials must be request at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Cap and Gown, a women’s honor society, was established in 1905. Their mission is to honor and bring together women who have been constructively active in student affairs and the community so that as a group, they may meet to maintain and serve the ideals of Stanford University. Among their activities is a scholarship program, which has been operating since 1924.
Description of the Collection
The records include constitution; newsletters, 1932-2007; the yearly calendar illustrated with images of Stanford University, 1941-83; membership book 1906-1996; history booklets, programs, brochures and mailings; photographs and printed items from their Centennial Celebration on March 5, 2005; other photographs, 1965-1997; survey of alumni, 1996; and clippings, 1965-1983.
Access Terms
Cap and Gown Society (Stanford University).; Women college students.
Collection Contents
- Records, Series 1
  - Alumnae Board rosters (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cartographicae Mappa Mundi (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings and press releases (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Constitution (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Centennial Celebration (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - History of Cap and Gown (booklets) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mailings (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Phillips, Susie - speech (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Programs, announcements, etc. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Treasurer's report (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cap and Gown Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cap and Gown News (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cap and Gown News (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cap and Gown News (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cap and Gown News (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Calendar (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Calendar (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Calendar (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Calendar (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Calendar (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Calendar (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Calendar (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2005-098
  - History of Cap and Gown (includes photograph) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Mailings (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Membership book (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Young Alumni Survey: Arts and Computers (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Young Alumni Survey: Public Service, Government, Environment (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Young Alumni Survey: Graduate School (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Young Alumni Survey: Business (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Young Alumni Survey: Law (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Young Alumni Survey: Education (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Young Alumni Survey: Medicine (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photos of Stanford used in calendars (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Card file "Social File" ["This file was organized in 1956-1957 as an aid to the social chairman in getting help for teas, banquet, and so on."] (Box 2)
- Photographs, Accession ARCH-2006-237
  - CDs of images (12) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Album of photos from the Centennial Celebration (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2008-224
  - Photographs - tapping (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs - tea at Hoover House (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Photographs - Southern California event (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photograph by Shmuel Thaler: Karen Senko and Sandra Day O'Connor (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History booklet revision (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Inductees (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bacon, Ros - memorial service program and letter from Charles Bacon (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Career Night (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Publicity Reports (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Memos and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Programs, invitations, printed items (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous historical sources (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Calendar, assorted records (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2009-257
  - History of Cap and Gown booklets (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellany: letters (1941, 2000), brochures (2004), and clippings (1963-1989) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook of clippings (with one photo) (Box 1, Folder 3)